transunion.com 2019-09-06

# Privacy Policy | TransUnion

Welcome to Trans Union LLC (“TransUnion”) and its family of companies. Please carefully read this online Privacy Notice (“Privacy Notice”) to understand how we treat your information on TransUnion.com (“Website”) and within our mobile applications (together with Website, “Online Services”).

This Privacy Policy applies to TransUnion and its domestic subsidiaries and affiliates, except for TransUnion Consumer Solutions, LLC, TransUnion Interactive, Inc. (TrueCredit and zendough), and TransUnion Rental Screening Solutions, Inc.’s [www.MySmartMove.com](http://www.mysmartmove.com/), who maintain their own privacy policies.

Please visit TransUnion’s Global Job Applicant Privacy Notice to learn how we treat personal information processed during the job application process.

### Information we collect

When you visit our Online Services, we collect information from you. We may collect your first and last name, email address, and agency/organization with which you are associated, account information (username and password), physical address, date of birth, telephone number (landline and/or mobile); a social security number; or certain other information, such as date of birth, employment information, certain credit card and loan account information, information about dispute(s) raised regarding your credit report, and information you provide to support the issue you raised.

We may also collect information about the device you use to access our Online Services, including device ID and advertising ID; your browser, your browsing history while using our Online Services (for example, the pages you view, how long you stay on each page, how often you return, and/or the site you visit when you leave us); the ads or online content you viewed, accessed, or clicked. We may collect your IP address and information related to that IP address, such as, geographical information, domain information, and the internet service provider used. We may collect information about your location. We use various technologies to determine your location, including IP address, Wi-Fi access points, and cell towers.

### Ways we collect your information

**Information collected directly from you**

We collect information directly from you when you create an account to access your credit report or to use the online dispute process. This includes information obtained from documents you provided to substantiate your claim.

We also collect other information you submit through our Online Services, such as requests to enroll in offers and events. We collect information when you complete an online survey and when you click a link. If at any time you wish to opt out of the email messages, you may click the opt-out link embedded in all email communications or contact us via email, phone, or mail. Please visit our [contact page](https://www.transunion.com/customer-support/contact-us-consumers) to learn how.

When you call in and speak with a customer service agent, we may ask for your email address so that we can email versions of certain postcards/letters to you related to your inquiry rather than sending postal mail.

**Information from Third Parties**

We may utilize data from third parties, such as your telecommunications provider, to help confirm your identity and prevent fraudulent access. It is likely that you authorize your telecommunications provider (AT&T, Sprint, T-Mobile, Verizon, etc.), to share your personal information for the purposes of fraud prevention and identity verification. The information they share, if available, may include your telephone number, name, address, email, network status, customer type, billing type, mobile identifiers (IMSI) and (IMEI), and other subscriber status details.  TransUnion limits the use of this information to prevent fraud and unauthorized access or disclosures of your personal information.

**Cookies and other technology (passive collection)**

We use cookies to enable you to sign in and to deliver content specific to you. A cookie is a small text file that a web server places on your computer or device when your browser accesses a website. A web server assigns cookies uniquely to you, and only a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you can read the cookies.

We use cookies for a number of different purposes. Some cookies are necessary for technical reasons; some enable an individualized experience; and some “remember” who you when you revisit our Online Services.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline some or all cookies if you prefer. TransUnion is committed to providing you choices to manage your privacy and sharing. Not accepting cookies may make certain features of the site unavailable to you. If you would like more information about cookies, you can visit <http://www.cookiecentral.com/n_cookie_faq.htm>.

Like many websites, we use retargeting, a cookie-based technology, to provide advertisements that we think our Online Services visitors may like. This type of retargeting works by placing a pixel, or small piece of code, on your computer when you visit our Website. The pixel ensures that our ads will be served to previous visitors of our Online Services.

We use Google Analytics, Optimizely, or other similar analytical tools to collect information in order to display and optimize advertisements and personalize your experience on our Online Services. As part of this service, we receive information collected from other websites that displayed our advertisements. This enables us to understand how our Online Services visitors, exposed to ads placed on other websites, interact with our Online Services. We may use this information to enhance or modify our campaigns that are designed to bring visitors to our Website. You may opt-out of this anonymous data collection and sharing activity by visiting the Google Analytics Privacy Overview web page and following the procedures noted under the Browser Opt-Out and Privacy Center information sections (search for these sites through [www.google.com](https://www.google.com/)).

### Purpose and use of your information

When you provide information, through our Online Services, we may use it for various reasons:

  * to communicate with you and internal parties, on a strict need to know basis, regarding the your credit report inquires and/or complaints;
  * to update our consumer credit database;
  * to verify your identity;
  * to prevent fraud and unauthorized disclosures of your personal information;
  * to record and demonstrate how we have conducted the dispute and complaint resolution process and arrived at a resolution; and
  * to comply with legal requirements, for example, to report on equal employment opportunities where required by law.

Access to consumers’ personal information in TransUnion’s consumer credit database is limited to: (1) entities with a permissible purpose to receive it, as defined in the Fair Credit Reporting Act (“FCRA”); (2) entities with a permitted use under Title V of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act; (3) companies who resell our data as permitted under law; and (4) companies who process data on our behalf.

Access to information not subject to the FCRA in this database may be provided to companies and other entities for research and other purposes.

Under the FCRA, we may provide information to companies that provide you with pre-approved offers of credit or insurance. If you prefer not to receive such offers, you may opt-out by calling 1-888-5OPTOUT or visiting [www.optoutprescreen.com](https://www.optoutprescreen.com/?rf=t).

Sharing your information

When you visit our Online Services, we may collect your name and email address, we may share that information with one or more third parties in order to administer the program and present such offers to you. In connection with the email registration program, our third-party email processor may use action tags (also known as single pixel gif or web beacons) to collect information concerning your use of our Online Services. Such third-party administrators are not authorized to use any such information for any other purpose. If you decide to register for emails, you may opt-out of receiving further emails at any time by using the opt-out provision at the bottom of every email.

If you provide your email to a customer agent as part of our pilot program to deliver updates regarding your account, TransUnion will only this information to communicate with you regarding your account.

**Market Research.** Your participation in market research activities is optional. Should you choose to participate, we may use information you provide to improve your experience with our products and services. We may engage third parties to assist us with our market research efforts who may retain aggregated information. However, all personal information you provide will only be used for our research purposes.

### Rights Regarding Your Information

**Access to Your Information**

You may order your TransUnion Personal Credit Report online at TransUnion.com. However, when you provide information on our Website, you should ensure that the information is accurate.

**Change Inaccurate or Incomplete Information**

If you believe that there is an error on your credit report, you may file a dispute.

**Opting-Out of Email Communications**

You have the choice to opt-out of email communications at any time by using the opt-out provision at the bottom of every email.

### Security

We take security seriously at TransUnion. We maintain physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to protect any data that we collect. We use security technologies to safeguard credit information and any information you provide us. TransUnion maintains policies, procedures, and compliance mechanisms, such as training, independent review and third-party verification of our stated practices, to ensure adherence to our information security plans and this Privacy Policy.

### Policy Regarding Children

We define children as individuals under the age of 16. Our Website is not intended for use by children and we do not knowingly solicit or collect information from children. Specific to our Digital Marketing business, we define children as individuals age 18 and younger and do not knowingly include them in our products and services.

Specific to our Digital Marketing business, we define children as individuals age 18 and younger and do not knowingly include them in our products and services.

### Our Digital Marketing Business

This section applies solely to our Digital Marketing services.

**Purpose and Use.** Through TransUnion’s Digital Marketing services, we enable our business partners to communicate with consumers in a digital environment. In an effort to provide relevant products and services to consumers, these businesses use our data and technology to create, deploy, and measure targeted advertising programs digitally. We collect information as outlined below and use it for permitted marketing uses. In addition, we may aggregate and depersonalize data for analytical purposes, to provide reporting to our business partners, and for measuring advertising performance. And as a part of enabling Digital Marketing services, we may use service providers.

**Data Collected.** The information we collect (“Marketing Data”) for our Digital Marketing business is segregated from traditional consumer reporting agency information. Marketing Data may include information on consumers, households, properties and businesses as well as nonpersonal aggregated information and advertising program performance data. Marketing Data includes information about consumers such as demographics, life events, public records, or firmographics. Demographic data includes information such as age, gender, income, occupation, education, and marital status. Life events data includes information such as a recent move or home purchase. Public records data includes information such as summarized U.S. Census data, geographic data, and property data from local tax assessor and recorded deed information. firmographic data includes information such as type of business, years in business, size of business, and job titles.

**Sharing Data.** We share Marketing Data with our business partners to facilitate the creation and deployment of digital advertising. For example, when we segment our data into groups of consumers (“Audiences”), we share it using unique identifiers (“Unique IDs”). We use a proprietary process to convert our data into Unique IDs that do not contain personally identifiable information. We may also share aggregated and depersonalized data with our business partners for analytical purposes, including measuring advertising performance and reporting. Many of our business partners are Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) members and/or Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) participants and are required to comply with those respective codes of conduct or principles.

**Choice.** We take our commitment to privacy seriously. If you prefer to opt out of receiving marketing messages, we recommend that you visit the Data & Marketing Association (DMA) and register on their consumer web site: https://dmachoice.thedma.org/. TransUnion will apply DMAChoice opt-outs to our Marketing Data to implement your preferences and comply with DMA guidelines. In addition, the DAA offers a WebChoices tool that allows you to choose company specific digital advertising preferences for your browser. Please visit http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/ to explore information about participating companies and to register your specific opt out preferences.

### Privacy Notice Changes

This notice may change from time to time. Please check our Online Services periodically for updates to this Privacy Notice. Any changes to this Privacy Notice become effective upon posting to our Online Services. By using our Online Services and the services described herein, you agree to the processing of personal information as discussed within this Privacy Notice.

Last reviewed: 6/17/2019

Effective Date: 6/18/2019
